<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>8a73bb11</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>8a73bb11-a3a8-4c75-a203-abb2e0629d96</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_create-a-retirement-fund</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>Create a Retirement Fund that gives you comfort in your sunset years </heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Retirement is a time for you to sit back and relax. A time to pursue your pet project and be free of the stresses of your work life. Another thing that you need to be free of is financial stress. Will your trusted old pension plan be able to meet all your needs in requirement? Most likely not. Thus, it is imperative that you supplement your pension plan with a retirement fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steps for creating a healthy and sufficient retirement fund&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a id="_anchor_1" href="file:///C:/Kamesh/Kotak%20Mahindra%20Bank/IEco%20Content/Articles%20Content/iecoarticlesfromcms/Retirement%20Planning_V1.docx#_msocom_1" language="JavaScript" name="_msoanchor_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Determine the needs &lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; before you can create a retirement fund, the first thing that you need to do is understand your retirement needs and determine the amount of money that you will require to fulfil those needs. There are plenty of projects that you can pursue in your retirement years. These could range from something as simple as starting a new hobby to packing your bags and travelling the world. The possibilities are infinite. Unfortunately, the funds are finite. So, once you have an idea of what you want to do in your retirement phase, the next step is to get a rough idea of your expenses. Break this up into money that you will need to fulfil your basic needs like food, shelter, daily expenses and medication, as well as, needs related to travel, hobbies or passions projects. In addition to generating income to meet your needs, you should also have a contingency fund that you can dip into in times of emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Assess current and future resources &lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; once you have set your goals and have prioritised them in order of importance, you need to figure out how you are going to finance them. The good thing is that you need not begin from scratch. I am sure that by the time you consider retirement, you would have amassed some wealth, investments and fixed assets. Many of you would already have an equity portfolio along with investments in the appropriate mutual funds, pension schemes and insurance products. Take these into account when planning for retirement. Additionally, also consider future resources like income from part-time employment.&amp;nbsp; Remember that your current income is your biggest resource and you need to start allocating a portion of your current income to retirement savings, as early as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A &amp;ldquo;Retirement&amp;rdquo; Investment Plan&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; ensure that your financial plan makes retirement planning a key goal. Create a specific investment plan for your retirement fund basis your risk profile, return requirement and time horizon. As an investor, you can have multiple financial goals. A well thought out investment plan should help you create a diversified portfolio that can accomplish each one of your financial goals. When creating a retirement investment plan, carefully consider the type of insurance policy you would like to purchase and evaluate your mutual fund investments. Also, consider making contributions to the National Pension Scheme (NPS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Be Disciplined &lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; one of the biggest risks an individual can encounter is outliving his retirement funds. The only way you can mitigate this risk is by planning for your retirement from an early age and by adopting a disciplined approach to investing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retirement should be treated as the beginning of a new journey. Astute financial planning is the best way to prepare for this journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_create-a-retirement-fund.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name/>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-01-10T13:11:55.485Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-01-10T13:11:55.485Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
</component>