<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>d29958e8</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>d29958e8-b8f3-4c99-a1d0-62055e44ee17</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_Buying Vs Renting – A debate that is heati 75a41127</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>Buying Vs Renting – A debate that is heating up</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Buying Vs Renting &amp;ndash; A debate that is heating up&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any conversation that ponders over the &amp;ldquo;buying vs renting&amp;rdquo; conundrum is likely to end up in a raging debate with the proponents of each passionately defending their corner. The choice between ownership and rental is influenced by a host of factors that include, but are not limited to, proximity to workplace, urban connectivity, access to basic amenities, easy access to public infrastructure, security and affordability. Cost, predictably, holds the maximum sway. Buying a home can also be a highly emotional decision as home ownership gives people a sense of security and belonging. While the ultimate choice is a personal one, it would be instructive to evaluate the relative benefits and shortcomings of each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cost &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying a house entails making a large one-time payment which can be split into a lumpsum payment and a monthly EMI for a fixed period of time. However, these are not the only costs associated with homeownership. Owning a house also comes with additional costs that could include property tax, maintenance and repair costs and insurance. Renting does not require a large upfront payment and tenants usually know the exact amount that they are going to spend on housing each month. However, in addition to the annual increments in rent, there is always the risk of a sudden and sharp increase in rents.&amp;nbsp; Financing either of these options requires two very different financial journeys. If you are looking to buy a house, then you need to build a substantial corpus to make a large down payment and ensure that you can comfortably service your EMI. This would require investing a majority of your money in equity and equity related investments. On the other hand, in order to meet your rental obligations, you need to invest in lower risk, liquid instruments like liquid funds since you would require the money in the short-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Commitment&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people believe that owning a house translates into financial security. A home gives people roots and is perceived as an investment that can grow over a period of time.&amp;nbsp; However, considering that a large part an individual&amp;rsquo;s current and possibly future income is invested in a home, it is also a long-term commitment, one that might not necessarily be easy to get out of. Renting, on the other hand, can be cheaper and offers flexibility for minimal responsibility. Renting gives more mobility and thus, becomes a convenient option if you are expecting to relocate, have a career that requires frequent transfers or you simply love exploring new options. On the other hand, renters face the risk of premature termination of the agreement where the owner asks the tenant to vacate the property before completion of the rent period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Management and troubleshooting&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renting is a service provided by the house owner - this comes with assistance in managing and financing major any major repairs that might be required while you are occupying the property. This can be a big advantage to people who are not inclined to assume such responsibilities.&amp;nbsp; Owning a house can be a huge responsibility, one that can sometimes be onerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you lay the foundation of your abode by buying a house or by renting one, you need to ensure that you are financially secure and are able to comfortably afford to pay for your choices. It is important to understand that the financial journey for each option is differentiated and requires judicious planning. Why delay when you can start planning this journey right away!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_buying-vs-renting---a-debate-that-is-heati-75a41127.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name>article_details</folder-name>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-03-17T15:39:16.877Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-03-17T15:39:16.877Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
	<action_label>3 min read</action_label>
</component>