<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>4d7a8e47</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>4d7a8e47-31f7-42f2-98e5-55a341239906</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcone_guide-to-buying-a-retirement-home</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>Guide to buying a retirement home</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, in India, retirement meant a time of your life when your kids would take care of you. The joint family system ensured that in the retirement phase parents lived with their now grown-up children and were well taken care of. However, with rising expenses and increasing migration, the trend is now changing. As people near their retirement age, they do not want to depend on their kids or other family members. Instead, they want to continue to be independent and lead their life on their own terms. Central to this feeling of independence is buying your own retirement home. While the prospect of buying a retirement home can be exciting it is important that it forms a part of your retirement planning. An investment in the National Pension Scheme (NPS) or an annuity plan can help you meet your expenses in your retirement phase. However, purchasing a home would require more money and thus, more judicious planning. Additionally, there are certain key factors that you must take into consideration before you buy a home for the retirement phase of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Five Step Guide to buying a Retirement Home&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Location and Accessibility&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; this can be a tricky one. There are many factors that can influence the choice of location. You may want to buy a home that is away from the hustle and bustle of the city but at the same time close enough to the necessary medical and lifestyle facilities. You might also want to go back to your roots and purchase a home in the place where you spent your childhood. Give some thought to these factors and ensure that you are close to your family so that help is at hand in case of emergencies. If you pursue a hobby like golf, then make sure that you do not have to travel too much to reach the golf course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Size and Structure&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; a simple fact of life is that as we reach our retirement age we tend to slow down a bit. Many of us are not as agile or as fit as we were in our younger days. The size and structure of the house should reflect this. Always remember that the upkeep of a large house is not only expensive but can be physically extracting. It is better to buy a single storey compact house that is spacious enough for you and your partner, but not so large that its upkeep becomes a burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Paperwork&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; it is highly unlikely that you would like to run from pillar to post in your old age. Thus, it is important that when you buy a home, all the paperwork is in place and the title is clear. If required, seek professional guidance to ensure that the transfer or purchase of property is clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Make a retirement plan that captures your desire for a retirement home&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; while you might purchase the retirement home closer to your retirement age, you must start preparing for it early on. This means that your retirement plan should include your goal to buy a retirement home and also account for the associated expenses. You can choose to invest in carefully selected blue-chip stocks and hold them for the long-term, make a lump sum investment in a large-cap fund or invest in a mid-cap or multi-cap mutual fund through a systematic investment plan (SIP). The key is to continue investing for a longer period of time so that you can benefit from the power of compounding and your portfolio can weather equity market volatility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prepare yourself emotionally&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; often, when you move houses you leave behind a community of friends and well-wishers. You are leaving a familiar surrounding for an unfamiliar one. It can be an emotional time. To cope with this change, you can consider involving yourself in social and philanthropic events to meet people and foster new relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id="_com_1" language="JavaScript"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcone_guide-to-buying-a-retirement-home.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name/>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-01-10T14:57:08.156Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-01-10T14:57:08.156Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
</component>