<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>4f246897</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>4f246897-2608-46f7-a938-60a1bf79ac6d</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_Planning for your destination wedding</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>Planning for your destination wedding</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Weddings can be one of the most joyous occasions of an individual&amp;rsquo;s life. It is something that most of us have dreamed about at some point in time or another. However, weddings can also be a very stressful time. There is a lot of planning that goes into making our dream wedding a reality. The destination or venue, the guest list, the catering, the flowers, the clothes &amp;ndash; the list is endless. Now, if you have set your heart on a destination wedding then be prepared to work hard. If a regular wedding can be stressful then a destination wedding can even, make you cry.&amp;nbsp; But, it need not necessarily be that way. Just a little extra planning and guidance can make your destination wedding an enjoyable and stress free experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Planning for your destination wedding&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weddings these days are becoming increasingly exotic and extravagant affairs. You can plan a royal wedding in Udaipur or have a fun and breezy wedding in Goa. The options are endless. Short of blasting off to space, you can choose to have your wedding literally anywhere. However, destination weddings can be a fairly costly affair. So, instead of bidding farewell to your dreams of a destination wedding, why don&amp;rsquo;t you and your partner tag &amp;ldquo;destination wedding&amp;rdquo; as an important financial goal and start investing for it now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first steps would be to arrive at the expected cost of the wedding and ascertain the time horizon. This will determine the level of risk that you can undertake and will accordingly help you diversify your investments across multiple instruments. The general thumb rule is - shorter the time horizon, lower is the risk taking ability of the investor. If your wedding is 18-24 months out, you can spread your investments across various fixed income bearing instruments. A small amount can be invested in a fixed deposit or a recurring deposit, while the balance can be invested in short-term funds that invest in debt securities with maturities between 1 to 3 years. If your destination wedding is less than 18 months away, then the best option would be to split the investment between a 12-month fixed deposit and a liquid fund. If you are really short on time, you might also consider applying for a personal loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Factor in the additional expenses&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ndash; destination weddings can have a host of additional costs that you need to take into consideration. From paying for the travel expenses of close family members to shelling out extra money to fly in your main chef or personal stylist, there are bound to be additional expenses. While your investment plan will take care of the overall cost of the wedding, it would be wise to use intermittent cash flows like bonus money or any extra savings made during the month to top up existing SIPs. This practice can potentially help you cover any additional expenses that might come up at the time of your wedding.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Give your guests a heads up &lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; for your guests, attending an &amp;ldquo;out-of-town&amp;rdquo; wedding means taking time off from their work and daily commitments to be there for you on your special day. It is important that you share your wedding plans with them in advance so that they can make the necessary arrangements in order to attend your wedding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Destination weddings, if planned well, can be magical. The key is to start planning and investing for the wedding well in advance so that you are prepared to deal with unexpected surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_planning-for-your-destination-wedding.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name/>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-03-17T16:40:51.136Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-03-17T16:40:51.136Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
	<action_label>3 min read</action_label>
</component>