<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>8516c01c</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>8516c01c-80d0-4a7c-93f5-8a5a906041f8</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_projects-you-can-pursue-in-retirement</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>Projects you can pursue in retirement</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;For a long time, retirement has been considered a time to turn off the alarm clocks and hang up your boots. However, times are now changing. Instead of looking at retirement as the end of a road, it is now being viewed as the start of a new journey. An exciting new phase of life where you can fulfil all those aspirations that you have so far not had the time or energy to pursue. However, in order to pursue these aspirations, you have to ensure that by the time you enter your retirement phase you are financially secure. The idea should be to start retirement planning from an early age and create a retirement corpus that can take care of all your basic requirements during this phase so that you feel secure and empowered to pursue your dreams. At the onset, this would entail creating a retirement fund that includes long-term equity and debt instruments along with investments in a pension scheme and the relevant life insurance products. Once you have this in place, you can pursue any dream that your heart desires. Here is a list of five projects that you can pursue in retirement.&lt;a id="_anchor_1" href="file:///C:/Kamesh/Kotak%20Mahindra%20Bank/IEco%20Content/Articles%20Content/iecoarticlesfromcms/Projects%20you%20can%20pursue%20in%20retirement_V1.docx#_msocom_1" language="JavaScript" name="_msoanchor_1"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Start a small consulting business&lt;/b&gt; - by the time you reach your retirement age, you would have spent at least 30 to 35 years in a particular domain or field. Having garnered a great deal of experience and expertise, you can choose to leverage it further by starting a small consulting business. This will give you an opportunity to use the skills built through your career along with the flexibility of managing your time. If you do not want to dip into your retirement savings, you can consider approaching a bank for a small business loan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Philanthropy &lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; &amp;nbsp;many of us want to give back to society. Unfortunately, the daily struggles of our lives leave us little time to fulfil this aspiration. Empowering the youth of tomorrow through education is one of the best ways of giving back to society. You could dedicate some of your time to teaching children or youngsters. You might want to go a step further and start an NGO for a cause that you feel very strongly about. However, if you wish to open an NGO or donate heavily to philanthropic causes then you need to plan your investments judiciously so that a substantial corpus is created specifically for this purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Travel&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ndash; there must be many of us who have at some point or the other wished to quit their jobs and travel the world. Well, retirement is the perfect time to finally take off and explore the world. Of course, you need to be well prepared financially, as well as, physically to undertake this project. Additionally, instead of financing your entire trip through your retirement fund, you can make investments closer to your retirement to specifically finance a world tour. Investments like term deposits, lump sum investment in a debt mutual fund or investment in an equity mutual fund through a systematic investment plan (SIP) can be considered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Write a book&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ndash; a majority of people across the world harbour the dream to write a book. Retirement can be the time when you finally put pen to paper and spin the tales you have always wanted to. While the book might not necessarily be a best-seller, finally completing it will definitely give you a sense of achievement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Start a new hobby&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ndash; now that you have the time, start a new hobby. Learn to sing or play a new instrument. Or pick up a game. Or learn Japanese cooking. The possibilities are infinite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you strap on those new boots and set forth on another adventure, remember that in order to have a comfortable retirement phase, you must start planning and investing for it from an early age. At sixty-five, the world is your oyster. Ensure that you enter it with a reliable financial cushion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_projects-you-can-pursue-in-retirement.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name/>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-01-10T13:09:02.621Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-01-10T13:09:02.621Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
</component>