<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>3f014551</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>3f014551-8dd3-4f0c-bbd5-9e92119a56df</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_destionation-europe</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>A European holiday for every kind of traveller</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Europe is the perfect holiday destination, luring travellers from across the world with its old-world charm, gastronomic delights, historic monuments and various cultural festivals. In 2018, more than one million Indians applied for tourist visas to visit Europe. Clearly, Europe is the holiday destination of choice for many Indians. It can be your next holiday destination as well. All you have to do is start planning now. Planning for what you want to do in Europe and planning for how you can afford your European vacation. For the latter, you need to start investing now. First and foremost, start investing in an equity mutual fund through a systematic investment plan (SIP). Next, evaluate investing a lump sum amount in a term deposit or a debt mutual fund. These investments should be specifically made to finance your grand European vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;For the former question, i.e. top things to do in Europe, we have a few suggestions. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Art &amp;amp; Culture&lt;/b&gt; - explore the masterpieces of Michelangelo and Da Vinci in Italy, the birthplace of Renaissance and marvel at the Mona Lisa at the Louvre in Paris. Europe is famous for theatre, music and art. In fact, Italy has the distinction of being home to the highest number of masterpieces than anywhere in the world. On the other hand, the Muse du Louvre in Paris has more than 38000 objects and 35000 artworks on display. A good number to beckon the art aficionado in you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mouth-watering cuisines&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;- from the pizzas and pastas in Italy, bratwurst in Germany to the tapas in Spain and the &amp;ldquo;light as air&amp;rdquo; pastries in Paris, Europe will tingle your taste buds like no other destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gorgeous Landscapes&lt;b&gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;- while the Swiss Alps will awaken the romantic in you, the beautiful beaches of Southern Spain will give you the best &amp;ldquo;chill&amp;rdquo; vibes. If neither the hills nor the beaches lure you then the staggering lagoons and glaciers of Iceland might. Or maybe you just fancy a romantic gondola ride in Venice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Breath-taking monuments&lt;b&gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt; - gaze at the Milan Duomo or visit Germany to get mesmerized by the tallest church in the world. Have dinner on the top floor of the Eiffel tower or relax in the gardens of a medieval castle in England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Festivals&lt;b&gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt; - have your Bollywood style moment at the Tomatina festival in Spain or explore the winter wonderland at the many Christmas markets in December. Visit the carnivals of Venice or plan a trip with your friends to enjoy Oktoberfest in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every kind of traveller can find something to enjoy in Europe. Now, as you go rushing to apply for your visa, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to meet your financial advisor and start investing for your European holiday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_destionation-europe.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name/>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-01-10T09:52:42.446Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-01-10T09:52:42.446Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
</component>