<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>a32d1c36</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>a32d1c36-a230-40ca-9114-36975dda8158</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_Create a budget with your spouse 34245012</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>Create a budget with your spouse</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Create a budget with your spouse&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Budgeting does not come easily to most of us. We live in a world of instant gratification where saving has lost much of its previous appeal. The challenges with budgeting get amplified in a marriage. Sometimes it is easy to get carried away with the moment and spend more than what is considered judicious. Marriage can mean extra income from two salaries and a decrease in expenses as many expenses get clubbed. On the other hand, it can also mean the opposite where a single income is used to support two people instead of one. You have now moved away from a sole proprietorship to a partnership and all important decisions should be made in consultation with your partner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone seems to have some advice to give when you start married life. What very few people tell you is how to create a workable budget with your spouse. The first and foremost step is to have the &amp;ldquo;talk&amp;rdquo; with your spouse early on. You must be proactive and not reactive with your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Determine household expenses:&lt;/b&gt; Divide your household expenses into variable and fixed expenses. Variable expenses could include groceries, phone bills, medical expenses etc. while fixed expenses could include rent, payment of insurance premiums or any other fixed recurring outflows. Also, take into consideration the impact of inflation on your future expenses. Due to inflation, the average cost of goods and services increases over a period of time. Assuming annual inflation of 5%, something that costs INR 100 today might cost INR 105 next year due to the impact of inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;List out the liabilities:&lt;/b&gt; Do you and your spouse already have existing liabilities? These could include existing EMIs on a home loan, existing education loans, credit card bills or even any regular pay-out made towards other family members. A list of the existing liabilities, their cost and the tenure is important to understand its impact on household savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Determine total household income:&lt;/b&gt; It is sometimes difficult to accept that once you are married, your income becomes the household income. You and your spouse should determine total income from all sources to arrive at the household income. This will not only include income from employment but also interest or dividend income received from investments made, either jointly or individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Make a note of discretionary spending:&lt;/b&gt; As the name suggests, these expenses relate to spending on things that you might not necessarily need but want. These need to be discussed in detail because they can often be a bone of contention between spouses and can single-handedly derail your monthly budget. The easiest way to deal with this would be to follow the 50-20-30 rule to budgeting which suggests that you should allocate 50% of your income to necessities, 20% of your income towards your financial goals and the balance 30% towards discretionary spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How will you divide the expenses? You need to decide whether you will have a joint savings account from which the expenses will be paid after pooling in a portion of combined income, or would you prefer to save and invest one salary and incur expenses from the other salary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Goal setting:&lt;/b&gt; As individuals, each of you would have your own goals that you wish to achieve. Additionally, once you get married, you would also have a host of combined goals that you need to plan for as a couple. It is important to account for both these types of goals when creating an overall household budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a budget that divides the responsibility of saving equally: After considering all of the above, create a workable budget that does not inordinately constraint any one person&amp;rsquo;s expenses and yet ensures that you reach your target monthly savings. Consider starting a monthly recurring deposit or investing in an equity systematic investment plan (SIP) with your monthly savings. The prospect of growing your savings will further encourage you and your spouse to stick to your budget. The longer you stay invested the more you can reap the benefits of compounding. For example, a monthly SIP of INR 15,000 with an assumed CAGR of 12%pa, can potentially grow to INR 35 lakhs in 10 years, INR 1.5 crore in 20 years and INR 5.3 crore in 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Use a budgeting app or software&lt;/b&gt; &amp;ndash; If all this becomes a bit too much to track, you can always use a budgeting app or an expense tracker to track your progress and get alerted whenever there is a deviation from your budgeting plan. It might also be wise to seek advice and consult a financial planner who can help you build a customised and robust long-term portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In marriage, it is important to work together as a unit and to keep the lines of communication always open. Having the talk on budgeting can be essential to marital and financial bliss!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_create-a-budget-with-your-spouse-34245012.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name>article_details</folder-name>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-03-17T15:24:20.718Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-03-17T15:24:20.718Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
	<action_label>3 min read</action_label>
</component>