<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>9c969e3a</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>9c969e3a-c375-4184-901a-8803933160b9</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_stepstocreate_holidayfund</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>5 Steps to creating a Holiday Fund</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Taking a holiday can mean different things to different people. For some, it is a much needed break from a hectic work schedule while for others it might be an annual family tradition.&amp;nbsp;Whatever may the reason be, vacations are becoming an integral part of our lives and a common millennial goal. Having a dedicated holiday fund can go a long way in making your holiday a fun and enjoyable experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steps for creating the Ultimate Holiday Fund&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Location, location, location&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; the most important thing is to zero in on a location. Are you looking to plan a simple weekend getaway or do you want to fly off to Europe over Christmas break? Do you want to explore the wonders of India or do you want to have a fancy foreign vacation? The location of your holiday will strongly impact your holiday budget, so better to have a few names on the wish list to get going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Determine the cost&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; before creating a holiday fund, you first need to determine how much money you need. Once you know your location, the next step is to evaluate the costs. First and foremost is the cost of the tickets and the hotel. The cost of the hotels can vary depending on the time of the year that you are visiting. For example, during summers and at Christmas time, hotels in Europe are generally very expensive while in offseason they offer good discounts. Next, list down essential items for the trip. There are things that you might need to purchase which will contribute to the overall cost of your trip. In addition, also include the cost of food, transportation at the holiday destination and miscellaneous travel expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Start investing to fund your holiday&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; there are two things that you need to know before you create your holiday fund. First is the total cost involved and the second is the time horizon. There will be many investment options available depending on when you want to take your holiday and the amount of money you require to make this dream a reality. In general, mutual funds can be a good investment option. If you plan to take the holiday in the next 6 months, then you can consider investing in a liquid fund. On the other hand, if you plan to take the holiday in the next 12 - 18 months, then you could consider starting a systematic investment plan (SIP) in a debt fund or a large-cap fund. It is always advisable to consult a financial advisor for optimal asset allocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Do more&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;ndash; while creating a holiday fund is a step in the right direction, you can always do more. Consider cutting down on unnecessary expenses and saving up some money monthly. You can use this extra cash to shop for essentials that you might need on the holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Involve the family&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ndash; if it is a family vacation that you are planning, then definitely involve the family. Create a picture board of the places you want to visit to encourage the family to save. Also, encourage your children to plan an itinerary and make a list of places that they would like to visit on the holiday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say that the journey can be as much fun as the destination. Make planning for your holiday as much fun as the holiday itself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_stepstocreate_holidayfund.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name/>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-01-10T14:55:51.668Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-01-10T14:55:51.668Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
</component>