<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>b9f767a8</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>b9f767a8-d588-4521-a952-f5822e1366cf</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_Investment advice for newlyweds</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>Investment advice for newlyweds</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Investment advice for newlyweds&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marriage is varyingly described as a union between two kindred spirits, an equal partnership or sometimes, even a merger. No matter what definition you settle on, you are likely to agree that communication on finances is important for marital bliss. Marriage is the beginning of a new journey, one that needs to be paved with financial security. As newlyweds, you must recognise the importance of saving and investing together in order to create a bright and comfortable future for yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few things that you should consider while having a discussion on finances and investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Determine your goals:&lt;/b&gt; Based on the income, expenses and existing liabilities, you should make a workable budget and list out your financial goals. This should be done after taking into consideration what you and your spouse envision in your future. Would you like to have kids? A big family? Would you like to buy a house or rent one? What would your retirement years look like? Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to ask questions and be honest with your expectations. Your financial security is very important. Hence, any goal based planning that you do should be preceded by a commitment to first creating a contingency fund that can provide a financial cushion during unforeseen exigencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Set SMART goals:&lt;/b&gt; Your short-term, medium-term, and long-term financial goals will have a strong impact on your overall budget. Short-term goals are typically those you want to achieve in the next three years. These could include things like buying a car or maybe saving for a holiday. Medium-term goals are those that have a time horizon of three to five years while the longer-term goals are usually more than five years out. These could include saving for a down payment on a house or investing in a business. The most important long-term goal that you will be saving for is your retirement. This requires saving and investing for most of your working life, which can be up to 40 years. Have a detailed discussion with your spouse and ensure that the goals you set are specific, measurable, achievable, realistic and time based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Invest wisely and invest early:&lt;/b&gt; This is one of the most important points that a couple needs to focus on. It is easy to get carried away dreaming and paying for a destination wedding followed by an exotic honeymoon. By the time you start thinking about investing, a good two years have flown by. Based on your combined risk appetite, liquidity and savings goal, you can choose to invest in a wide variety of investment avenues. For the short-term goals, it is advisable to invest in low risk instruments like fixed deposits, recurring deposits or liquid funds as these are mostly fixed income bearing ie. there is zero to very low volatility in their returns. For your medium to long-term goals, you can consider a mix of assets that could include individual stocks, equity mutual funds and debt mutual funds. As the time horizon increases, so does an investor&amp;rsquo;s ability to absorb risk. The longer you stay invested the more you can reap the benefits of compounding. For example, a monthly SIP of INR 15,000 with an assumed CAGR of 12%pa, can potentially grow to INR 35 lakhs in 10 years, INR 1.5 crore in 20 years and INR 5.3 crore in 30 years. Additionally, it is wise to invest early when liabilities are on the lower side. Once you start a family your ability to save is severely compromised. Prudent investments at the start of your marriage will generate large benefits over the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Protect what matters most:&lt;/b&gt; It is often said that when you get married, two becomes one. Thus, it is important to protect that &amp;ldquo;one&amp;rdquo;. One of the first few things that you should do after getting married is to buy a life insurance policy and a health insurance policy. This will ensure that your spouse is well protected in case of your premature death while any adverse health related incidents do not put a big dent on your lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marriage is a rollercoaster ride, replete with ups, downs, twists and curves. Let your marriage be the start of a happy, beautiful journey built on a bedrock of trust and financial security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_investment-advice-for-newlyweds.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name/>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-03-17T16:30:47.800Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-03-17T16:30:47.800Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
	<action_label>3 min read</action_label>
</component>