<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>2f6daf16</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>2f6daf16-b2f6-4718-a44e-604896985622</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_investing-in-experiences 1be0a56e</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>Experiences can be priceless</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;We live in a world that is obsessed with consumption. Everybody is in a race to buy something. However, there are also many people who believe that an excess of material things leads to &amp;ldquo;stuffocation&amp;rdquo;. They understand that happiness over material items fades away while the joy of experiences stays with us. There would have definitely been instances when many of you would have fondly recalled the amazing time that you spent on a family holiday or the thrill you felt when you went sky diving in Dubai. Even though experiences cannot be captured in entirety, they shape our thought process and perspectives. While the value of experiences can be priceless, they do come with a price tag. However, judicious financial planning and investment management can help you broaden your horizons and enable you to experience the &amp;ldquo;extraordinary&amp;rdquo; life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Experience the tranquillity at Kailash Mansarovar &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pilgrimage to Mount Kailash and the Mansarovar lake can be a deeply moving and surreal experience. Mount Kailash, the abode of Lord Shiva, is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most revered holy places. At its feet, languidly lies lake Mansarovar, the highest freshwater lake in the world. A yatra to Kailash Mansarovar takes around 24 days and can cost anywhere between INR 1.5 lakhs to INR 2.5 lakhs. However, don&amp;rsquo;t let this figure deter you. Plan your yatra in advance to get physically and financially fit. You can consider investing in a debt mutual fund or a 1-year term deposit. Additionally, you can also consider investing a small amount in an equity fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Experience the thrill of sky diving in Dubai&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adventure sports can be a different kind of spiritual experience. The fear and adrenalin rush associated with adventure sports can definitely create extraordinary moments. The closest that a man can come to experiencing flight is sky diving. While there are a few places in India where you can skydive, you might want to choose Dubai as your sky diving destination. Sky diving in Dubai can cost anything between INR 30,000 to INR 45,000. Also, there will be additional travel related expenses like flight tickets, visa and accommodation which could amount to INR 50,000. In order to finance this experience, you can consider investing in a liquid fund or a term deposit. Additionally, do not forget to buy the appropriate insurance cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Experience the world of the Incas at Machu Picchu in Peru&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A visit to the ruins at Machu Picchu in Peru can be a humbling, as well as, an inspiring experience. One of the three main civilizations in Mesoamerica, the Incas built this towering citadel on a 7970 ft. mountain ridge, back in the 15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. While the trek to the site can be arduous, a first glance of the rising sun over the ruins of Machu Picchu can leave us awestruck. You instantly know that you are experiencing one of seven modern wonders of the world. A visit to Machu Picchu can cost around INR 1,50,000 to INR 2,00,000 per person. This includes the cost of air tickets, visa, accommodation for 3 days in Cusco and a trip to the site. Such a trip needs to be planned in advance in order to ensure that you have sufficient money to finance the trip. You can consider various investment options like a term-deposit, debt mutual fund or a liquid fund. You can also consider starting a systematic investment plan (SIP) in an equity mutual fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say that in order to experience life to the fullest you must step out of your comfort zone and travel to places far and near. We say that in order to experience life to the fullest start investing now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_investing-in-experiences-1be0a56e.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name>article_details</folder-name>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-01-10T13:01:29.557Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-01-10T13:01:29.557Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
</component>