<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>d29958e8</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>d29958e8-b8f3-4c99-a1d0-62055e44ee17</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_Roti, Kapda aur Makaan – What does housing</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>Roti, Kapda aur Makaan – What does housing mean for millennials?</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p align="center" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Roti, Kapda aur Makaan &amp;ndash; What does housing mean for millennials?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Indian society, home ownership is symbolic of stability and success. &amp;ldquo;Buying a house&amp;rdquo; is a goal for a majority of Indians as owning a house serves to be as much of a status symbol as a necessity. Since buying a house usually involves a large financial outlay, it is almost always partially financed through personal savings and partially by a home loan. Consequently, banks and housing finance institutions offer different types of home loans that come with flexible repayment options and variable tenures. Individuals are also making &amp;ldquo;buying a house&amp;rdquo; one of their key financial goals and accordingly investing in relevant instruments like equity mutual funds, direct equity and debt funds to create a sizeable corpus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What are the millennials doing?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a millennial, &amp;lsquo;buying a house&amp;rsquo; might or might not be on your wish list. An important trend to register is that millennials are fairly flexible when it comes to choosing between ownership and rental. Unlike the previous generation for whom buying a house was imperative, the current generation is fairly comfortable with renting. They are happy to explore options where they can give their own premises on lease and then stay on rent in another, more desirable area that is probably closer to their workplace. We are also seeing the concept of micro-living gaining currency amongst the millennials. Micro-living basically propagates self-contained living in a small unit where an individuals&amp;rsquo; basic housing needs are fulfilled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology plays an important role in the lives of millennials. Today, more and more people are looking for technology enabled properties that offer a sustainable living environment. Homeowners are becoming more conscious of their environment and are showing a preference for green and open spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Always be financially prepared to buy a home&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While a house has traditionally been viewed as a safety net, there is now an increasing emphasis on value for money. Compact homes with potential for resale, well-connected locations, and projects by reputed builders are now gaining traction not just for their &amp;ldquo;security&amp;rdquo; value but also as an investment value. Millennials are constantly debating the buying versus renting option. Real estate investments can form an integral part of an individual&amp;rsquo;s portfolio as an investment in real estate can give you rental yield in addition to a sharp upside from potential price appreciation. Rental yield is simply the rate of return generated on a property by way of rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it is to invest in the government&amp;rsquo;s affordable housing projects or to buy a luxurious prime property, one needs to start investing for the same early on. Even if you think that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to buy a house you might change your mind in the future. But you can&amp;rsquo;t get up one day and say, &amp;ldquo;I want to buy a house today&amp;rdquo;. It requires judicious financial planning, one that you should begin as soon as you start earning. This is important for even those people who are sure that they would prefer to rent a house rather than buy one. In addition to ensuring that you have sufficient money to regularly meet your rental obligations, money also needs to be saved to pay the lump sum security deposit amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, the real estate market in India has been a sellers&amp;rsquo; market, plagued with unfair practices that were detrimental to the home buyer. Buying a house was a cumbersome task, one that drained away our savings, as well as, our mental peace. However, regulatory changes like GST and RERA are designed to work in favour of the home buyer by making the market more equitable, transparent and simple. Additionally, the easy availability of home loans and the adoption of digital platforms by sellers is further augmenting the housing market in India. Now, you can easily convert your dream of buying a house into reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_roti--kapda-aur-makaan---what-does-housing.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name/>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-03-17T17:02:40.280Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-03-17T17:02:40.280Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
	<action_label>3 min read</action_label>
</component>