<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/articledetails</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>f01cebbe</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>f01cebbe-0a65-4b58-a1b0-eb520c5d38fb</objectId>
	<internal-name>welcome_Don’t let your EMI become a burden</internal-name>
	<pre_heading/>
	<heading>Don’t let your EMI become a burden</heading>
	<sub_heading/>
	<description>&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let your EMI become a burden&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in our own home is something that most of us hope to accomplish in our lifetime. While a majority of home buyers use a home loan to finance their purchase, you still need enough money to make a heavy down payment in addition to ensuring that your monthly income will be sufficient to service your EMI. All of this can seem very daunting, however, there are some ways that you can plan your EMIs so that the EMIs on your home loan do not become a burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The size of your EMI depends on your loan size &amp;ndash; Borrow less&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying a house is something that takes a lot of planning and research. You can split this goal into two parts. One is the need to create an investment corpus that can sufficiently finance the down payment on your new home and two is to ensure that you are able to service the EMI in a comfortable and consistent manner without it becoming a burden on you. Thus, it is important that you only borrow an amount that you can afford and comfortably repay. This you can achieve by ensuring that you save up as much as you can before you avail a loan. Since &amp;ldquo;buying a house&amp;rdquo; is usually a 10 to 12-year dream, you can allocate a larger portion of your investment to equity funds and direct equities either through a lump sum investment or by investing through a systematic investment plan. Equities can be relatively volatile but are expected to generate potentially higher returns over a longer time period. As you approach the end of the investment time horizon, consider moving this investment to liquid funds or a one-year fixed deposit to ensure that the money accumulated is preserved. Additionally, you can also choose to allocate a small portion to debt funds or even foreign equities. This way, when you reach the point where you want to buy a house, you will have a sufficiently large corpus to make a down payment on your home, thereby, minimising the home loan amount and consequently the EMI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Take stock of your expenses&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have availed the home loan, the first thing that you need to do is take stock of your monthly expenses. Bifurcate your expenses into essentials and discretionary and make an attempt to cut down on your discretionary expenses. A good way to ensure that you are adhering to your plan is to have a separate account for servicing the loan. This will help you keep track of your expenses and encourage you to cut expenses, wherever possible. Or you can simply choose to adopt the 50-20-30 rule that suggests that you allocate 50% of your income to necessities, 20% to savings and investments and the balance 30% to discretionary expenses. Increasing your SIP amount every year in the proportion of your salary increase can help you reach your goal faster. For example: assume that you need to accumulate INR 75 lakh to make a down payment on your home. Now, if you start a monthly SIP of INR 15,000 at an assumed rate of 12%, it will take you ~15 years to reach the target corpus. However, if you increase the SIP amount by 10% per annum, then you will be able to accumulate INR 75 lakh in ~12.5 years. By increasing the SIP amount by 10% per annum you will be able to reach your goal 2.5 years earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Invest your savings &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The excess money that you save every month should be immediately invested. You can choose to top-up an existing SIP with the additional money that you save monthly. This will not only inculcate savings discipline but also give a fillip to your savings. At the end of a few years, you might discover that the small amount that you were investing monthly has grown into a healthy corpus &amp;ndash; one that you can use to prepay a part your home loan so that the EMI amount or tenure reduces. Similarly, any unexpected windfall gains should either be immediately invested or used to make a prepayment on the loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Create an emergency fund&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must also create an emergency fund that covers at least 6 months of EMIs. There can always be unexpected circumstances that hinder your ability to service your EMI.&amp;nbsp; In such an instance, you need to have a backup or a contingency fund that you can dip into in your time of need. An emergency fund needs to be relatively safe and liquid. You can consider investing in a liquid fund or in a 6-month to 1- year fixed deposit for the same. Simply use our calculator to arrive at the amount of money you need to invest to create a robust emergency fund. You can also choose to utilise the EMI sweep-in facility by linking a fixed deposit investment to your savings/loan account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judicious planning can help you accomplish a great deal. Don&amp;rsquo;t let the fear of an EMI stand in the way of buying your dream home. Just be astute in your EMI management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<file-name>welcome_don-t-let-your-emi-become-a-burden.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name/>
	<createdDate>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-12-23T14:03:19.662Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-03-17T16:48:41.010Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-03-17T16:48:41.010Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
	<action_label>3 min read</action_label>
</component>