<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/dream_detail</content-type>	<display-template/>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>496eab0a</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>496eab0a-990a-4657-af87-82b3368af5ed</objectId>
	<internal-name>Retire Early 63b802fa</internal-name>
	<details_heading>Plan a Holiday</details_heading>
	<detail_desc>Retirement is a time for you to sit back and relax. A time to pursue what you love and be free of the stresses of your work life and most importantly forgetting about financial stress. Retiring early and pursuing your passion is the talk of the town now. Many people dream of shutting off the alarm clock early and pursue what they love doing. To do that, you need to be free of finanicial stresses. Create a retirement corpus and let these worries go away!</detail_desc>
	<offer_label>Do you know?</offer_label>
	<offer_desc>Let's say your monthly expenses are Rs. 40000 and you plan for your retirement after 30 years. Your expenses at the time of your retirement will become ~Rs. 3 lakh (at 7% inflation). To live on your savings for another 15 years, you will need to accumulate Rs. 5 Crore. This is not as tough as it looks like. Achieve this by doing a per month SIP of Rs. 25,000 for next 30 years to be financially independent even at the time of retirement. Have you ever thought about this? Well! Its never late, act now. Dont forget to consider your EPF fund in your retirement planning</offer_desc>
	<terms_label>Happy Kotak360 stories</terms_label>
	<terms_desc>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manish works in a bank and have been shrewd with managing money. Manish planned for his retirement for 20 years. Leveraging on long term market conditions, Manish made a corpus good enough to sustain his entire life. He followed asset allocation strategies and managed money with diverse intruments&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</terms_desc>
	<action_label>Pursue this dream</action_label>
	<file-name>retire-early-63b802fa.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name>dream_details</folder-name>
	<createdDate>2019-11-23T03:15:22.324Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-11-23T03:15:22.324Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-03-31T13:10:10.958Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-03-31T13:10:10.958Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
</component>