<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component>
	<content-type>/component/commoncomponents2</content-type>	<display-template>/templates/web/entry.ftl</display-template>
	<merge-strategy>inherit-levels</merge-strategy>
	<objectGroupId>ce7b</objectGroupId>
	<objectId>ce7b4348-aee8-2c36-9c94-0b8c7094419d</objectId>
	<description>We will complete paperless offline eKYC using Aadhaar authentication. Please keep your Aadhar number handy which you have to enter on UIDAI website and your mobile number should be registered with your Aadhaar number</description>
	<internal-name>Start Investment</internal-name>
	<heading>Let’s get ready to invest</heading>
	<footer>I hereby give my free consent that I understand Aadhaar Paperless</footer>
	<file-name>start-investment.xml</file-name>
	<folder-name/>
	<footer_elements item-list="true">	<item>	<label>I hereby give my free consent that I understand Aadhaar Paperless Offline e-kyc is a secure, digitally signed sharable document which I have to generate by accessing UIDAI resident portal and upload it on Kotak Investment Advisors Limited (KIAL) platform for offline verification of my identification without sharing the Aadhaar number.</label>
	</item>	<item>	<label>The details will contain Name, Address, Photo, Gender, DOB, hash of registered Mobile Number, hash of registered Email Address and reference id which contains last 4 digits of Aadhaar Number followed by time stamp in a digitally signed XML.</label>
	</item>	<item>	<label>I agree to voluntarily use my Aadhar details for doing full KYC of my Kotak 360 account as per the above process and authorize Kotak Investment Advisors Limited (KIAL) to fetch my personal details from the Aadhaar Paperless Offline e-kyc details uploaded by me on  Kotak 360 platform to authenticate and verify my profile.</label>
	</item></footer_elements>
	<createdDate>2019-11-12T13:03:54.231Z</createdDate>
	<createdDate_dt>2019-11-12T13:03:54.231Z</createdDate_dt>
	<lastModifiedDate>2020-01-27T14:19:26.363Z</lastModifiedDate>
	<lastModifiedDate_dt>2020-01-27T14:19:26.363Z</lastModifiedDate_dt>
</component>